Guide to the Ardath W. Burks Papers, 1928-1996
Special Collections and University Archives, Rutgers University Libraries
- VI. SUBJECT FILES, 1949-1994, (2.3 cubic feet)
  - Yatoi Conference: Programs and Proposals, 1983-1985 (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Yatoi Conference, 1983-December 1984 (Box 24, Folder 10-11)
  - Yatoi Conference, 1985 (Box 25, Folder 1-3)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, circa 1979 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous Griffis, Kusakabe Research, Undated (Box 25, Folder 5-6)
  - Miscellaneous Material Japanese Language, Undated (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous Material, Undated (Box 25, Folder 8-9)
- VII. LECTURES AND PAPERS, 1938-1995, (3.6 cubic feet)
  Arrangement: by subject.
  Summary: grouped by subject.
  Material generated by or pertaining to Burks' scholarly pursuits within academia. This series includes articles, published and unpublished, authored by Burks; documentation relating to panels and conferences in which Burks participated, including papers and abstracts; material from Burks' public speaking engagements; teaching materials utilized by Burks; material from the New Jersey Seminar on Asian Studies (1962) and Columbia's University Seminar on Modern East Asia: Japan (1969-1990); papers, articles, and book chapters accrued by Burks, although he did not author them. Document formats include correspondence, lectures, articles, programs, memoranda, publication drafts, itineraries, newspaper clippings, course materials, abstracts, event programs, and dissertation abstracts and chapters.
  Each subject grouping also contains miscellaneous documentation, such as itineraries for speaking engagements or correspondence with editors of publications. The folders relating to the New Jersey Seminar on Asian Studies contains working drafts of papers presented by various scholars within the seminar.
  There are several documents of interest within this series. In 1993, Burks wrote a retrospective commentary accompanying his 1958 (unpublished) article, "Understanding Asia," which sketches some of his thoughts regarding his career and the development of Asian Studies as a discipline. The teaching materials include documentation of the "Traditions and Transition in Asia" course, the first East Asian course offered at Rutgers University. Amongst the materials by others which Burks collected is a pamphlet distributed by the American Committee for Non-Participation in Japanese Aggression (1939) and "Academic Reorganization in New Brunswick, 1962-1978: The Federated College Plan" by Richard McCormick (1978).
  - Articles Published, 1940-1941 (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Articles Published, 1946-1958 (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Articles Published, 1940-1941 (Box 26, Folder 1-4)
  - Articles Published, 1958-1970 (Box 26, Folder 5-6)
  - Articles: Enola Gay, 1995 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Book Reviews, 1948-1992 (Box 26, Folder 8-10)
  - Book Reviews, Asian American Review, 1984-1993 (Box 27, Folder 1-2)
  - Book Reviews, American Historical Review, 1963-1980 (Box 27, Folder 3-5)
  - Book Reviews, Choice, 1965-1982 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Book Reviews, Infantry Journal, circa 1944-1947 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Book Reviews, Journal of Asian Studies, 1963 (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Book Reviews, Perspective, 1978-1992 (Box 27, Folder 9-10)
  - Encyclopedia Americana, 1973-1994 (Box 27, Folder 11-12)
  - Encyclopedia Britannica, 1958-1995 and Undated (Box 27, Folder 13-15)
  - World Book Encyclopedia Tear Sheets, 1963 (Box 27, Folder 16)
  - Japan Society, 1907-1982, 1982 (Box 27, Folder 17)
  - Publication Announcements, 1949, 1956 and 1984-1986 (Box 27, Folder 18)
  - Reviews of Burks' Works, 1954-1994 (Box 27, Folder 19)
  - Westview Press Correspondence, 1982-1984 (Box 27, Folder 20)
  - Westview Press Correspondence, 1987-1991 (Box 27, Folder 21)
  - Articles Unpublished, 1941-1993 (Box 28, Folder 1-2)
  - Articles Unpublished, "Understanding Asia," 1958, 1993 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous Papers, 1947-1981 and Undated (Box 28, Folder 4-8)
  - Reader Reports, 1961-1984 (Box 28, Folder 9-10)
  - Reader Reports, 1970 and 1972 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Reader Reports, 1985-1992 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Papers and Panels, 1950-1982 (Box 29, Folder 3-9)
  - Papers and Panels, 1987-1992 (Box 29, Folder 10-12)
  - Papers and Panels: Commentary, Undated (Box 29, Folder 13)
  - Papers and Panels: Japan Panel Discussant at AHA, 1950 (Box 29, Folder 14)
  - Papers and Panels: Council on Foreign Relations, 1956 (Box 29, Folder 15)
  - Papers and Panels: Conference on Japanese Foreign Policy, 1963 (Box 29, Folder 16)
  - Papers and Panels: LUCE Workshop on Japanese-American Relations, 1979 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Papers and Panels: Fourth Conference, WCCES, 1980 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Papers and Panels: Commentary, 1979 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Papers and Panels: Commentary, 1982 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Lectures, 1940-1974 (Box 30, Folder 5-14)
  - Lectures, 1975-1995 and Undated (Box 31, Folder 1-8)
  - Lectures: Japan, 1958-1959 (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - Lectures: RU-ALL, 1996 (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - Television Appearances, 1967-1968 (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - Teaching Materials, 1948-1993 and Undated (Box 32, Folder 1-8)
  - Teaching Materials: University of Michigan Center for Japanese Studies, 1954 (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - Teaching Materials: Summer Institute, Delaware, 1956 (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - Teaching Materials: Summer Institute, Temple, 1957-1958 (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - Teaching Materials: Summer Institute, Philadelphia, 1960 (Box 32, Folder 12)
  - Teaching Materials: Summer Institute, Rutgers, 1960-1962, 1969, and 1973 (Box 32, Folder 13)
  - Teaching Materials: Summer Institute, Rutgers, 1960-1965 (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Teaching Materials: Summer Institute, Hawaii, 1966, and 1968 (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Teaching Materials: RU-ALL, 1993 (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Teaching Materials: RU-ALL, 1995 (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - New Jersey Seminar on Asian Studies, 1962 (Box 33, Folder 5-8)
  - Columbia University Seminar on Modern East Asia: Japan, 1964 (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - Columbia University Seminar, 1969, and 1975 (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - Columbia University Seminar, 1982-1984 (Box 34, Folder 1-2)
  - Columbia University Seminar, 1987-1990 (Box 34, Folder 3-5)
  - Columbia University Seminar, 1993 (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - Conference on Modern Japan, 1930 (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - Collected Papers, 1938-1939 (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - Collected Papers, 1958-1978 (Box 34, Folder 9-15)
  - Collected Papers, 1979, 1982-1985, 1990-1993, 1995 and Undated (Box 35, Folder 1-17)
  - Collected Papers, Undated (Box 36, Folder 1-2)
  - Collected Papers: International Institute for Environmental Affairs, 1972 (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Collected Papers: International Education at Rutgers, 1973-1983 (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - Collected Papers: Jane Burks, Undated (Box 36, Folder 5)
- VIII. COLLECTED PUBLICATIONS, 1951-1992, (1 cubic feet)
  Summary: arranged chronologically; publications of the International Center of Rutgers University and publications in Japanese are grouped separately.
  Publications collected by Burks. Publication types include booklets, pamphlets, newsletters, bulletins, periodicals, scholarly journals, and annual reports.
  Within the general publications is material authored by Junjiro Amakawa, Clark L. Beck, Ardath Burks, Otis Cary, Emerson Chapin, Robert Flershem, Yoshiko Flershem, Fumiko Fujita, Hirakawa Sukehiro, Ezra Vogel, and Masao Watanabe.
  - General, 1951-1973 (Box 36, Folder 6-11)
  - General, 1974-1989 (Box 37, Folder 1-10)
  - General, 1990-1992, 1994 and Undated (Box 38, Folder 1-5)
  - International Center, 1970-1983 (Box 38, Folder 6-9)
  - International Center, 1982-1985 (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - International Center for Japonisme, 1995 (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Japanese Language, 1969-1974, 1979-1984, 1986, and Undated (Box 39, Folder 3-10)
- IX. COLUMBIA UNIVERSITY SEMINAR ON MODERN EAST ASIA: JAPAN, 1961-1965, (2 cubic feet)
  The collected working papers presented in Columbia's University Seminar on Modern East Asia: Japan. The seminar was one of the first on-going academic seminars devoted to studying Japan within an academic context.
  - Papers presented, 1961-1965 (Box 40, Folder 1-29)
  - Papers presented, 1965-1970 (Box 41, Folder 1-30)
  - Papers presented, 1970-1974 (Box 42, Folder 1-27)
  - Papers presented, 1974-1978 (Box 43, Folder 1-34)
  - Papers presented, 1978-1983 (Box 44, Folder 1-29)
  - Papers presented, 1983-1990 (Box 45, Folder 1-30)
  - Papers presented, 1990-1995 (Box 46, Folder 1-22)
- OVERSIZE MATERIAL, 1929-1996, (4 cubic feet)
  Summary: arranged by series.
  The oversize material are listed according to the appropriate series above but are filed separately.
  - PERSONAL FILES: University of Cincinnati Map, 1939-1941 (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - PUBLIC RELATIONS FILES, 1953 and 1959 (Box 47, Folder 2)
  - MILITARY SERVICE FILES, 1942-1945 (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - MILITARY SERVICE FILES: Miscellaneous, 1945 (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - MILITARY SERVICE FILES: Maps of Japan, Undated (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - CORRESPONDENCE AND DOCUMENTS: General, 1950-1951 (Box 47, Folder 6-7)
  - CORRESPONDENCE AND DOCUMENTS: General, 1977 (Box 47, Folder 8)
  - CORRESPONDENCE AND DOCUMENTS: General, 1979 (Box 47, Folder 9)
  - CORRESPONDENCE AND DOCUMENTS: General, 1987 (Box 47, Folder 10)
  - CORRESPONDENCE AND DOCUMENTS: General, 1994 (Box 47, Folder 11)
  - LECTURES AND PAPERS: Articles Published, 1959 (Box 47, Folder 12)
  - LECTURES AND PAPERS: Papers and Panels, 1968 (Box 47, Folder 13)
  - LECTURES AND PAPERS: Teaching Materials, 1992-1993 (Box 47, Folder 14)
  - PERSONAL FILES: Norwood High School: The Mirror, 1929-1932 (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - PERSONAL FILES: General, 1977-1978 (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - PUBLIC RELATIONS FILES, 1990-1992 (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - CORRESPONDENCE AND DOCUMENTS: 1945, 1953, 1969, 1973, 1975-1975, 1979-1981 and 1983-1985 (Box 48, Folder 4-13)
  - CORRESPONDENCE AND DOCUMENTS, 1987, 1989, 1991, 1996 and Undated (Box 49, Folder 1-5)
  - TRAVEL FILES: Japan, 1951-1952 (Box 49, Folder 6)
  - TRAVEL FILES: Japan, China, 1980 (Box 49, Folder 7)
  - TRAVEL FILES: Pre-Yatoi Conference, 1985 (Box 49, Folder 8)
  - TRAVEL FILES: Yatoi Conference, 1985 (Box 49, Folder 9)
  - SUBJECT FILES: Cincinnati Council on World Affairs, 1968 (Box 49, Folder 10)
  - SUBJECT FILES: International Center for Japonisme, 1990 (Box 49, Folder 11)
  - SUBJECT FILES: Sister Cities, 1991 (Box 49, Folder 12)
  - SUBJECT FILES: United Nations Conference, 1972 (Box 49, Folder 13)
  - SUBJECT FILES: Yatoi Conference, 1985 (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - SUBJECT FILES: Miscellaneous Correspondence, circa 1979 (Box 50, Folder 2)
  - SUBJECT FILES: Miscellaneous Japanese Language Material, Undated (Box 50, Folder 3)
  - LECTURES AND PAPERS: Panels and Papers, 1973 (Box 50, Folder 4)
  - LECTURES AND PAPERS: Panels and Papers, 1981-1982 (Box 50, Folder 5)
  - LECTURES AND PAPERS: Collected Papers: American Committee for Non-Participation in Japanese Aggression, 1939 (Box 50, Folder 6)
  - LECTURES AND PAPERS: Collected Papers, 1953 (Box 50, Folder 7)
  - LECTURES AND PAPERS: Collected Papers, 1967 and 1979> (Box 50, Folder 8-10)
  - LECTURES AND PAPERS: Collected Papers, Miscellaneous, Undated (Box 50, Folder 11)
  - COLLECTED PUBLICATIONS: Japanese Language Material, 1979 (Box 50, Folder 12)
- X. PHOTOGRAPHS (photograph box), 1940-c.1993, (.15 cubic feet)
  Summary: color and black and white prints; reproductions from the Griffis collection; negatives; slides; scrapbook.
  Photographs of Burks, his family, his professional activities, and materials related to Griffis research. Also includes a scrapbook from the Rutgers Alumni visit to Fukui University in 1978.
  - Ardath Burks Portraits (15), Undated (Box 51)
  - Jane Burks Portraits (3), Undated (Box 51)
  - Jane and Riki Burks Portraits (5), circa 1950 (Box 51)
  - University of Minnesota Cosmopolitan Club (1), 1940 (Box 51)
  - Japanese Bankers Program (1 image with 2 negatives), 1974 (Box 51)
  - The New York Fukui Club (1), 1995 (Box 51)
  - Connor Graham Hughes (1), circa 1993 (Box 51)
  - Areta (1), 1991 (Box 51)
  - Willow Grove Cemetery (1), 1968 (Box 51)
  - W. E. Griffis' Grave, 3 corresponding slides 1981 (Box 51)
  - Catherine Street, Philadelphia, 4 corresponding slides 1981 (Box 51)
  - Reproductions of Griffis-related portraits (9) (Box 51)
  - Griffis material (15), Undated (Box 51)
  - Griffis-related negatives, With corresponding contact prints (132), Undated (Box 51)
  - Unknown Provenance (1), 1964 (Box 51)
  - Unknown Provenance, Rutgers Alumni Visit to Fukui University Scrapbook (11), 1978 (Box 51)
Name and Subject Terms
Personal Names
Burks, Ardath W.; Burks, Jane Lyle (Virginia Jane Lyle).; Griffis, William Elliot, 1843-1928.; Kaneko, Tadashi, 1934-; Matsumura, Mayoshi; Miki, Yukiharu, 1903-1964.; Shibata, Tokue, 1924-; Tanabe, Tatsuz¯o, 1929-; Yim, Yong Soon.
Corporate Names
Yatoi Conference.; American Association of University Professors.; Association for Asian Studies (AAS).; Northeast Asian Council (Association for Asian Studies).; United States. Navy.; United States. Office of Naval Intelligence.; Mid-Atlantic Region AAS(MAR); New Jersey Association of Colleges and Universities (NJACU).; Columbia University. Seminar on Modern East Asia.; University of Michigan. Center for Japanese Studies in Okayama.; Tokyo Metropolitan University;; Council on International Educational Exchange.; Association for Asian Studies.; Northeast Asia Regional Council.; Fukui University.; International House of Japan (Tokyo, Japan).; Rutgers College--Alumni and alumnae--Japan.; Rutgers University. Special Collections and University Archives.; Rutgers University. Jane Voorhees Zimmerli Art Museum.; Rutgers University. Rutgers Association of Fukui; Rutgers University. Academy for Lifelong Learning.; Rutgers University. International Center for Japonisme.; Sister Cities International.
Subjects
International education.; World War, 1939-1945.; Education--Japan--History.; Japanese students--New Jersey--New Brunswick--History.; Japan--Politics and government--1868-.; Japan--Politics and government--1945-.; Japan--Civilization--Western Influenced.; Japan--Civiliztion--1868-1912.; Japan--Officials and employees, Alien.; Japan--History--Meiji period, 1868-1912.